[Music]
Blessings everyone. This is Chris Kennel
from the rawadvantage.com, registered
holistic nutritionist, raw food
lifestyle coach, and raw chef. Today I
have a special Christmas gift for you.
Raw vegan sushi. The best ever. Let's
get into it. Baby, I like it. Raw
advantage likes it raw. Baby, I like it.
Yeah, baby.
All right, guys. So, I'm really excited
to share this recipe. I bought a whole
bunch of this certified organic raw
vegan nori from raw nori.com. I'm not an
affiliate or anything like that. I just
really enjoy it. And I've had a hard
time over the years getting good quality
vegan, certified vegan nori. A lot of
the standard stuff out there is kind of
questionable. There can be little teeny
bits of uh crustaceians and other
animals in there. I did a whole post
about this in the past, plus made my own
raw vegan nori recipe called better than
nori. It's all from land plants instead
of aquatic plants, so it's a little
easier to do. So that's going to be down
below if you want to make your own nori.
Otherwise, this stuff's pretty damn
good. raory.com. So I've been really
impressed and making a lot of different
sushi.
And I wanted to bring to you guys a
special trick. You know, in the past,
making sushi, making raw sushi, you
know, use cauliflower rice, but it
usually falls apart. And I figured out a
nice little trick to make it stick
together and taste a heck of a lot more
authentic and just be way more fun. So
when you're cutting it, it doesn't just
fall apart and blah blah blah, right?
So, you guys want to get into the
recipe? You know, and you know, I'm
going to let you know something else
really fun, too. This is going to be
recipe number one of two for Christmas
for you. So, this is going to be the
first one. It's the regular sushi rolls
with the seaweed on the outside. And the
second one will be next week with the
inside out rolls with the rice on the
outside. I have a couple tricks for that
one to make the rice stick and stay so
it looks perfect and again doesn't fall
apart in your hands. So, let's jump
right into the recipe. So, what you're
going to need is 460 gram or one pound
of cauliflower, 100 g of ginger peeled.
You can use the back of a spoon. An
eighth a cup of chia seeds. I prefer
white. One half of a lemon or about four
teaspoons of lemon juice. 150 grams of
cucumber. I prefer these little guys. 75
g of red pepper. One avocado, which is
about 180 g. And 25 g green onion. And
for equipment, you're going to need
a knife and a cutting board, a sushi
rolling mat,
a food processor or the Vitamix blender.
And if you're using a food processor,
then also the Vitamix blender or a seed
grinder or a coffee grinder. This is
just a magic bullet that has a seed
grinding attachment. So, let's start off
with the rice. So, we're going to start
with this cauliflower. Now, this is one
small cauliflower or about 2/3 of a
medium cauliflower. It's one pound with
all the leaves and everything off it.
I'm a little bit exact in this recipe
because it can be a little bit finicky
and if you're going to make a whole
bunch more rolls, then you want to have
your ratios right. So, we're making four
rolls, which is a a pretty decent meal
for me actually. Four rolls with the one
avocado, especially if I'm having a
fruit starter. It may be two portions
for some people and some people might
want to make a little bit more. But
we're starting with this one lb or 460 g
of cauliflower. And I'm going to rinse
it off. This is actually an important
step. You just want to lightly rinse it
off. Clean it. Make sure that it's uh
got no dirt or anything on it. It's not
organic. It's good to wash it anyway.
Washing it. Getting all the excess water
off of it. I'm not going to dry it
completely. just getting it pretty darn
dry. So, we have our cauliflower nice
and washed. And while it's sitting
there, I'm going to take the ginger. You
want to start with the ginger first. And
again, this is 100 grams already
pre-eled. So, you just use the back of a
spoon or a knife. I'm going to chop this
up just into little medallions.
I like a lot of ginger. If you don't
like ginger so much, you can omit the
ginger or cut it in half. But even
though this looks like a huge amount,
it's actually not a ton in the recipe.
It doesn't overpower it. So, we're going
to put that into the food processor,
put the lid on, and pulse this up until
it's a nice peeled rice texture.
There we go. It's useful to have a
spatula on hand, which I usually don't
like to do, but it's useful in this
circumstance.
Another pulse.
There we go. And now, once we've got
that started, we can start putting some
of this cauliflower in there. I like to
start off by putting about 1/2 of the
cauliflower with the pulseed ginger in
there. And then we'll finish the rest of
the cauliflower in a second batch. Now,
we put that ginger in there first
because we want it as fine as we can get
it. But the cauliflower you actually
don't want quite as fine as you can get
it. You still want some of that texture
and consistency that's a little bigger,
kind of like rice. So, we got a little
bit more than half in there. And we're
going to pulse this right up. Basically,
you just pulse it until you don't see
any big chunks going around. And if one
won't go away and it's getting small,
then you just open it up and take those
big chunks out for the next batch. I'm
going to take this square Pyrex dish.
You don't have to have one of these, but
you'll see why it's useful in a minute.
And pour the cauliflower rice right in
there. Taking out any big chunks, if
any, are in there still. Might need to
get that trusty spatula.
There we go.
smells amazing. And we'll get the rest
of the cauliflower in there.
If you don't like cauliflower or you
just want to try something different,
you can also use hikima. It works very
well. You just want to chop it into
medium bite-sized pieces before throwing
it into the food processor to get kind
of an even chop. I've even done it with
like carrots and other fun stuff like
that. But cauliflower,
I'd say it's probably the best
personally. Pulse this up.
Let's pour this right in to that Pyrex
dish. All right. So, now we have all
this beautiful rice. And this is how I
used to do my sushi, just like this. But
I figured out a few tricks. First, we're
going to take those four teaspoon of
lemon juice and just pour it on top of
the rice. This gives it a little bit
more of an authentic kind of sushi rice
flavor cuz they usually use rice wine
vinegar. If you're not opposed to it,
you could use apple cider vinegar, but I
find that this lemon works perfectly.
So, we just want to give that a little
bit of a stir around. Try and make sure
that that just lightly coats the rice so
it's all just a teeny bit wet. And it is
just a teeny bit wet from washing it
earlier. And then I'm going to take the
white chia seeds and put them into the
seed grinder. Now, you want to get whole
seeds rather than already ground cuz
when they're already ground, then
there's much more chance that the fats
are going to oxidize and go rancid. And
so, you want to keep your seeds and nuts
good quality, raw, in a cold place,
fridge or freezer, to last the longest.
Only take them out when you need them.
Fresh grind if you're using it. So, this
has a little grinder blade. Going to put
that on top
and pulse it in here. again. Otherwise,
you can use a coffee grinder or the
Vitamix.
[Laughter]
There we go. We just want it nice and
ground up into a chia flour. Look at
that. Can you see that? Oh, look at
that's beautiful. So, we're just going
to pour this over top of the rice nice
and evenly.
1/8 a cup actually stretches out to a
lot. And we're going to stir it up.
You want to make sure that you mix it up
really well so that the chia powder
really kind of goes around to every
single little nook and cranny mixed
together with the beautiful cauliflower
rice, lemon juice, and ginger. It's
really aromatic, looks great, and this
is the secret to get the rice to stick
together. So once we've got that
decently stirred up, what we're going to
do is take a little uh pie crust thing
or your hands and just press it down
into the pan so everything kind of
sticks together a little bit. Try and
make it fairly evenly. This is why I did
use this square little dish. You can use
just a regular bowl. It all works really
well. We're just going to squish that
down so you can see it's nice and tight
in there. And then take a knife and cut
into four sections, even sections. And
then you know exactly how much rice goes
into each sushi roll. Now, we'll just
set that aside so it can chill for a
little bit. We're going to want to get
the rest of the ingredients all ready
and chopped up so that we can make the
sushi a heck of a lot easier. So, what
we're going to do is take the two baby
cucumbers. Of course, again, you can use
regular cucumbers. I like to chop off
the end. So, I'm just going to place
them together. Chop off those little
ends. That can be a little snack.
There we go.
And then we're just going to cut them
into quarters by cutting them lengthwise
one way, spinning it, and cutting it
lengthwise the other. So,
then you have these four perfect sticks.
I'm going to set these up here.
And that's right. If you did that right,
those two mini cucumbers end up being
eight cucumber sticks, which means two
per roll, right? Oh,
we got a kitty.
She wants to go outside, but it's really
cold.
So, here we have the 75 g of red pepper.
This is actually just the side one half
of a red pepper. So it's kind of two
sides cuz they're kind of like usually
shaped like fours, right? So I like them
to be perfect flat like this. So it
might end up being that you need about
120 or 30 g of red pepper and chop off
the top and the bottom to get this
perfect 75 g like this. And this is
super simple. All we're going to do is
chop it in half and then chop those in
half and then chop each of those so that
each sushi roll gets four of these
little guys. So there we have all the
red pepper sticks. These two green
onions. What I'm going to do is chop off
just a little b bit of the bottom whites
and I'll save that for a sauce perhaps.
And we have these two sticks. I'm just
going to cut them in half lengthwise.
And then each sushi roll gets one half.
And the avocado will slice last by
cutting in half. And then each quarter
cutting into three slices.
All right. So, we got everything ready.
We got the rice, the cucumbers, the red
peppers, the avocado, the green onions,
and the nori. What are we missing? A
little bowl of water just to seal the
sushi. So, we're going to start by
taking one of the nori sheets and we'll
put it shiny side down on the sushi mat.
Take the rice and we'll take one quarter
of it and just scoop it on just on the
bottom third.
We go. And now the secret here is we
want to press the rice down. We're going
to leave about an inch at the top and
about a half an inch at the very bottom
of the sushi mat. If you want, you can
use a little pie scoop to flatten it
out. And you can even put it to the edge
of the sushi mat and squish right up to
there so it gets a nice flat edge. Once
you've got it spread out perfectly,
you're going to take your avocado. So,
take three slices of avocado
and put that along the bottom. You
usually like to do a big slice, the
smallest one the other way, and then the
second biggest one. Take a green onion,
put it right across.
Take two cucumbers, put them right
across. They might be a little bit long.
And if you need to
bite a little chunk off of it,
four red peppers.
right in the middle.
And then what we're going to do is
carefully line it up on the rolling mat
so that it's right at the bottom. Take a
dab of water with your fingertips.
Spread it across the top.
We'll pinch this and grab the topping so
they don't move over. And bring it all
the way to the other side.
You want to squish it down. Not as hard
as you can, but pretty firmly. Roll this
back a little bit. And then continue
rolling until it's nice and sealed.
Squish it good.
And you have one perfect sushi roll. I
call these sushi snakes. And sometimes
I'm lazy and I just eat them like this,
like snakes. it is nice and fancy to cut
them to make it more traditional. So,
what we're going to do is cut them right
after rolling them. I've tried waiting
and it works way better if you cut them
right after rolling them. So, I'm just
going around the outside and pushing a
little bit of the rice that started to
come out back in there so it's nice and
solid. You'll notice that there isn't
rice dumping all over the place. That's
one of the benefits of that chia so it
nice and sticks. I'm going to take a
sharp sharp knife. Now, I'm using a
serrated knife cuz I don't have any
super Japanese ninja knives that are so
sharp that they work well. If you have a
really sharp one, that works. Otherwise,
a sharp serrated knife. We're going to
go right in the middle and cut it in
half carefully with a nice sawing motion
regardless if you have serrated or not.
Then you can place them beside each
other. Cut them both in half
and in half again.
Careful not to chop your fingers off.
And cut the last two.
There we go. That's what we like to see.
Place them on a nice plate and then
we'll continue and roll all the rest of
the sushi. Let's continue rolling.
A little tip, it can be a little bit
easier if you wet your knife or just
clean it off between each sushi roll.
Well, there you have it. A raw vegan
sushi feast fit for a king or queen.
Seriously, ridiculously delicious. But
to try it, right? So, I like them plain
like this. Let's go for it.
[Music]
Seriously, one of my favorite raw vegan
dinners. Nice thing to switch up from my
curries and all the other recipes. You
can check out my Rawome recipe playlist.
Over 100 free recipes. My Raw Advantage
app, over 100 recipes in there, and all
my other fancy books, trinkets, all the
links are below. But these are honestly
perfect and delicious as is, but you can
use any of your favorite dips or
dressings. I got over 21 in my Naturally
Rawome dressings book. And also,
Naturally Rosome Sauces teaches you how
to make your own sauces, dips, and
dressings so you become a bonafide raw
vegan sauce master. We all know it's all
about the sauce. And we'll tease her.
I'm going to have a lot more sushi and
sushi sauces and stuff upcoming in the
future. But uh as I mentioned, next week
will be the inside out rolls. And I hope
you absolutely enjoy these. Hit like and
hit that bell so you get notified first
when the new videos pop up. And you
know, just give a thumbs up or a thumbs
down if you didn't like it. I really do
hope you like it though. As always,
wishing you much. Peace, love, and
seasonal fruit.
The best raw vegan sushi.
Go ahead, give it a try. The rice
sticks.
Oo. Don't forget to check out my raw
recipes playlist in the top left, the
video just for you in the top right.
Subscribe for more videos in the bottom
right and get your three free ebooks in
the bottom left. Grab your free raw
recipe app available on iPhone and
Android with over 100 free raw recipes,
common fruit and vegetable calorie
breakdown, freaking raw and food
combining chart, shopping cart function,
and so much